{"tossups": [{"question": "This work's protagonist falls in love with Yugao, who is killed by the spirit of one of his mistresses. This novel's title character falls in love with Lady Fujitsubo due to her resemblance to his mother. (*) Murasaki Shikibu wrote, for ten points, what early Japanese novel about the adventures of an egotistical \"shining\" prince?", "answer": "The Tale of Genji (accept Genji Monogatari)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Tale of Genji</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Tale of Genji", "Tale of Genji"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Genji Monogatari"}, {"question": "This biome is home to most members of the genus Phyllobates, which includes batrachotoxin-generating frogs. Most instances of this biome are tropical, and are home to scarlet (*) macaws and many undiscovered species that live high in the canopy. For ten points, name this biome where numerous species of tall trees thrive due to abundant precipitation.", "answer": "(tropical) rainforest", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>rainforest</u></b>", "acceptable": ["rainforest", "rainforest"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "tropical"}, {"question": "Cities on this body of water include Le Havre, Calais, Brighton, and Dover, whose sheer white cliffs sit on the shoreline of this body of water. In 1994, a Eurostar train (*) tunnel underneath this body of water was opened. The islands of Jersey, Guernsey, and the Isle of Wight lie in, for ten points, what channel that separates France from the island of Britain?", "answer": "English Channel (accept English Channel after \"channel\" is read; accept The Channel before \"channel\" is read)", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>English</u></b> Channel", "acceptable": ["English Channel", "English"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept English Channel after \"channel\" is read; accept The Channel before \"channel\" is read"}, {"question": "In a novel by this author, Rosemary Hoyt comes between the protagonist and his wife, Nicole Diver, who is based on this author's wife, Zelda. In another novel by this author, (*) Jordan Baker cheats at golf, and the narrator's West Egg neighbor has an affair with Daisy Buchanan. For ten points, name this author of Tender is the Night and The Great Gatsby.", "answer": "F(rancis) Scott (Key) Fitzgerald", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "F Scott (Key) <b><u>Fitzgerald</u></b>", "acceptable": ["F Scott (Key) Fitzgerald", "Fitzgerald"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "rancis"}, {"question": "In this religion, Puja is the act of welcoming a deity or spirit as a guest, and may include offerings of ghee. This religion's Trimurti includes a preservation god whose consort is (*) Lakshmi. The Ganges River is holy to, for ten points, what Indian religion whose primary gods are Vishnu, Brahma, and Shiva?", "answer": "Hinduism (accept word forms like Hindu faith)", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Hinduism</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Hinduism", "Hinduism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept word forms like Hindu faith"}, {"question": "Thomas Cromwell helped this man dissolve his country's monasteries, beginning two years after his 1534 Act of Supremacy made him the head of the Church of (*) England. This man broke with Rome partially because Pope Clement VII refused to annul his marriage to Catherine of Aragon. For ten points, name this English king from the House of Tudor who married six women.", "answer": "Henry VIII (prompt on \"Henry\")", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Henry VIII</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Henry VIII", "Henry VIII"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on \"Henry\""}, {"question": "This economic quantity is increased in quantitative easing while the Federal Reserve lowers the yield of Treasury notes. On a graph of price vs. quantity, this quantity's curve slopes upward, because more good are (*) produced at higher prices. For ten points, name this economic concept, the amount of a good that can be produced, often compared against a good's demand.", "answer": "supply (accept money supply; prompt on money until it is read)", "subcategory": "Social Science", "category": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>supply</u></b>", "acceptable": ["supply", "supply"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept money supply; prompt on money until it is read"}, {"question": "Vault complexes were discovered in this material in the 1980s and are still of unknown utility. Nutrients are delivered by the \"streaming\" of this material around plant cells. Glycolysis takes place in this material, in which (*) ribosomes can float. For ten points, name this gel-like material within a cell that contains organelles and is surrounded by the cell membrane.", "answer": "cytoplasm (accept cytosol) \ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>cytoplasm \ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc</u></b>", "acceptable": ["cytoplasm \ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc", "cytoplasm \ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc\ufffc"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept cytosol"}, {"question": "During this man's re-election campaign, he ran with Henry Wilson instead of incumbent Vice President Schulyer Colfax, who was under investigation for taking bribes from a railroad construction company, (*) Credit Mobilier. For ten points, name this winner of the 1872 and 1868 Presidential elections, a popular former Civil War general.", "answer": "Ulysses S. Grant", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ulysses S. Grant</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ulysses S. Grant", "Ulysses S. Grant"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "On this show, Joyce tries to communicate with Will by chopping through the walls of her home. Barb Holland disappears at a party she attends with Nancy Wheeler on this show, in which a group of boys learn about the (*) Upside-Down from an Eggo-loving, psychokinetic girl named Eleven. For ten points, name this 1980s-nostalgia mystery show produced by Netflix.", "answer": "Stranger Things", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Stranger Things</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Stranger Things", "Stranger Things"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A movement with this number in Hector Berlioz's Symphonie Fantastique includes a \"Witches' Sabbath.\" \"Fate knocking at the door\" describes a symphony with this number that has a (*) \"short-short-short-long\" motif written by Beethoven. For ten points, give this number of flats in the key signature of D-flat major and number of performers in Franz Schubert's Trout Quintet.", "answer": "five (accept fifth symphony, fifth movement, etc.)", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>five</u></b>", "acceptable": ["five", "five"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept fifth symphony, fifth movement, etc."}, {"question": "This author wrote \"The Hunting of the Snark\" and a poem about a hero who uses a \"vorpal sword,\" according to a story told by Humpty-Dumpty. In a novel by this man, a little girl finds cakes and drinks that (*) change her size, and meets the Cheshire Cat and the Mad Hatter after following a White Rabbit. For ten points, name this author of \"Jabberwocky\" and Alice's Adventures in Wonderland.", "answer": "Lewis Carroll (accept Charles Lutwidge Dodgson)", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "Lewis <b><u>Carroll</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Lewis Carroll", "Carroll"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Charles Lutwidge Dodgson"}, {"question": "This man said that \"some blue-eyed devil [...] had imposed\" his ancestors with a slavemaster's name in an autobiography co-written by Alex Haley. In March 1964, this man broke with a movement led by Elijah (*) Muhammad, and was killed less than a year later. For ten points, name this African-American activist and one-time member of the Nation of Islam who replaced his birth surname, Little, with a single letter.", "answer": "Malcolm X (accept Malcolm Little before it is read; accept el-Hajj Malik el-Shabazz)", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Malcolm</u></b> X", "acceptable": ["Malcolm X", "Malcolm"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Malcolm Little before it is read; accept el-Hajj Malik el-Shabazz"}, {"question": "In this field of mathematics, the unit circle can illustrate how the Pythagorean identities work. Functions used in this branch of mathematics often prefer inputs of (*) radians, rather than degrees. For ten points, name this branch of mathematics, named from the Greek for its primary focus of measuring triangles, in which special functions like sine and cosine are used.", "answer": "trigonometry", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>trigonometry</u></b>", "acceptable": ["trigonometry", "trigonometry"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man's Rope disguises reel changes with clever panning. In a film by this man, a wheelchair-bound photographer is convinced that his neighbor's wife has been murdered. This director used screeching (*) violins to punctuate the stabbing death of Marion Crane, who dies in a shower in the Bates Motel. For ten points, name this director of films like The Birds, Rear Window, and Psycho.", "answer": "Alfred Hitchcock", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Alfred Hitchcock</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Alfred Hitchcock", "Alfred Hitchcock"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This goddess blinded Tiresias for siding against her in an argument and tempted Paris with control of Europe and Asia. After Argus was killed, this goddess placed his eyes in the tail of her sacred bird, the (*) peacock. This mother of Hephaestus took revenge on Leto for having children with her husband, the king of Olympus. For ten points, name this Greek goddess of marriage and wife of Zeus.", "answer": "Hera (prompt on Juno until \"Greek\" is read)", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Hera</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Hera", "Hera"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on Juno until \"Greek\" is read"}, {"question": "This country fought France in the 1838 Pastry War, during which a general from this country lost his leg, then had it buried with military honors. That injury occurred during a failed raid on the occupied fort city of (*) Veracruz in this country. For ten points, name this country which celebrates an 1865 victory against the French at Puebla on Cinco de Mayo, and which was often led in battle by Santa Anna.", "answer": "Mexico (accept United Mexican States or Estados Unidos Mexicanos)", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mexico</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Mexico", "Mexico"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept United Mexican States or Estados Unidos Mexicanos"}, {"question": "The discovery of this concept was assisted by Galileo's ball-rolling experiment which, without friction, would have continued horizontally forever. One definition of this concept notes that, under zero net external force, an object will maintain (*) constant velocity. Newton's first law defines, for ten points, what concept that describes an object's resistance to changes in its motion?", "answer": "inertia", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>inertia</u></b>", "acceptable": ["inertia", "inertia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Two stories recorded by this author concern Gerda's tears melting an ice shard in Kai's heart and a child who tells a title ruler that he is naked. In addition to \"The (*) Snow Queen\" and \"The Emperor's New Clothes\" this man wrote about a girl who gives up her voice to marry a prince at the risk of turning into sea foam. For ten points, name this Danish recorder of folk tales like \"The Little Mermaid.\"", "answer": "Hans Christian Andersen", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Hans Christian Andersen</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Hans Christian Andersen", "Hans Christian Andersen"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One type of these structures forms between two dipoles and causes water's high melting point. Another type of these structures cannot twist, due to p-orbital overlap; that type exists in sp2 [\"s p 2\"] hybridized molecules as a \"double\" type. These structures can also be classified as (*) covalent or ionic. For ten points, name these attractive structures that hold atoms together within molecules.", "answer": "chemical bonds (accept hydrogen bond, double bond, single bond, covalent bond, ionic bond; prompt on intermolecular forces)", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>chemical bonds</u></b>", "acceptable": ["chemical bonds", "chemical bonds"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept hydrogen bond, double bond, single bond, covalent bond, ionic bond; prompt on intermolecular forces"}], "bonuses": []}